Stop that! Stop that!
Go on, be off! Go away.
And you, be off!
Bloody weather.
The tale of Sir Lancelot.
One day, lad, all this will be yours.
. What, the curtains?
. No, not the curtains.
All that you can see,
stretched out over the hills and valleys.
That'll be your kingdom, lad.
. But, Mother.
. Father, lad.
. But, Father, I don't want any of that.
. Listen, lad.
I built this kingdom up from nothing.
When I started here, it was a swamp.
Other kings said I was daft
to build a castle on the swamp.
But I built it all the same to show them.
It sank into the swamp.
So, I built a second one.
That sank into the swamp.
So, I built a third one. That burned down,
fell over, then sank in the swamp.
But the fourth one stayed up.
And that's what you'll get, lad.
. The strongest castle in these isles.
. But I don't want any of that.
. I'd rather...
. Rather what?
I'd rather just...
...sing.
. Stop that.
You're not going into a song
while I'm here!
In 20 minutes, you're marrying a girl...
...whose father owns
the biggest tracts of open land in Britain.
. But I don't want land.
. Listen, Alice.
. Herbert.
We live on a bloody swamp,
we need all the land we can get.
. But I don't like her.
. Don't like her?
What's wrong with her?
She's beautiful, she's rich.
She's got huge...
...tracts of land.
I know, but I want the girl
that I marry to have...
...a certain special something.
Cut that out!
You're marrying Princess Lucky,
so you'd better get used to the idea!
Guards!
Make sure the Prince doesn't leave
the room until I get him.
Not to leave the room,
even if you come and get him.
No. Until I come and get him.
Until you come and get him,
we're not to enter the room.
No, you stay in the room
and make sure he doesn't leave.
. And you'll come and get him.
. Right.
We don't need to do anything,
apart from stop him entering the room.
. No. Leaving the room.
. Leaving the room, yes.
. All right?
. lf...
. lf we're...
. Yes?
Look, it's quite simple.
You stay here and make sure
he doesn't leave the room.
. All right?
. I remember.
Can he can he leave the room with us?
No, you just keep him in here,
and make sure...
Yes! We'll keep him in here, obviously.
. But if he had to leave...
. No. Keep him in here!
. Until you, or anyone...
. Not anyone, just me.
. Just you...
. Get back.
. Right?
. Right.
We'll stay here until you get back.
. And make sure he doesn't leave.
. What?
. Make sure he doesn't leave.
. The Prince?
. Yes, make sure he doesn't leave.
. Yes, of course!
I thought you meant him!
It seemed a bit daft
me having to guard him when he's a guard.
. Is that clear?
. Quite clear. No problems.
Right.
. Where are you going?
. We're coming with you.
I want you to stay here,
and make sure he doesn't leave.
I see, right.
. But, Father...
. Shut it, and get that suit on.
And no singing!
Go and get a glass of water.
. Well taken, Concorde!
. Thank you, sir, most kind.
And again!
Over we go! Good, steady!
Now, the big one!
Come on, Concorde!
Message for you, sir.
Concorde, speak to me!
"To whoever finds this note...
"...I have been imprisoned by my father...
"...who wishes me to marry
against my will.
"Please, please come and rescue me.
"I am in the tall tower of Swamp Castle."
At last! A call! A cry of distress!
This could be the sign
that leads us to the Holy Grail!
Brave Concorde,
you shall not have died in vain!
I'm not quite dead, sir.
You shall not have been mortally wounded
in vain!
I think I could pull through, sir.
. I see.
. I think I'm all right to come with you.
No, sweet Concorde! Stay here.
I will send help as soon as
I have accomplished a daring and...
...heroic rescue in my own particular...
. Idiom, sir?
. Idiom!
. No, I feel fine, actually, sir.
. Farewell, sweet Concorde!
I'll just stay here, shall I, sir?
Yeah.
Hey!
You're not allowed to enter the room...
Fair one, behold your servant,
Sir Lancelot of Camelot.
. I have come to take... I'm terribly sorry.
. You got my note!
. I got a note.
. You've come to rescue me?
. Well, no, you see...
. I knew someone would.
I knew that somewhere out there,
there must be someone...
Stop that! Stop it!
Who are you?
. I'm your son.
. No, not you.
. I'm Sir Lancelot, sir.
. He's come to rescue me, Father.
. Let's not jump to conclusions.
. Did you kill all those guards?
Yes. Sorry.
. They cost 50 pounds each.
. I'm awfully sorry.
Don't be afraid of him, Sir Lancelot.
I've got a rope ready.
You killed eight wedding guests and all!
Well, you see,
I thought your son was a lady.
I can understand that.
. Hurry, Sir Lancelot! Hurry!
. Shut up!
. You only killed the bride's father!
. I didn't mean to.
Didn't mean to?
You put your sword through his head!
. Oh dear, is he all right?
. You kicked the bride in the chest!
. It's going to cost me a fortune!
. I can explain.
I was in the forest, riding north
from Camelot when I got this note.
. Are you from Camelot?
. Hurry, Sir Lancelot!
I'm a knight of King Arthur, sir.
Very nice castle, Camelot.
Very good pig country.
. Is it?
. I am ready!
. Would you like to come have a drink?
. That's awfully nice of you.
. I am ready!
. I mean, to be so understanding.
You see, when I'm in this idiom,
I sometimes get a bit carried away.
Now, this is the main hall.
We'll have all this knocked through...
. There he is!
. Bloody hell.
. Hold it, please!
. See what I mean? I get carried away.
I'm really most awfully sorry.
Sorry, everyone.
He's killed the best man!
Hold it, please, hold it.
This is Sir Lancelot...
...from the Court of Camelot,
a brave and influential knight.
. And my special guest here today.
. Hello.
He killed my auntie!
No, please!
This is supposed to be a happy occasion!
Let's not bicker and argue
about who killed who.
We are here today to witness the union
of two young people...
...in the joyful bond of holy wedlock.
Unfortunately, one of them,
my son Herbert...
...has just fallen to his death.
But I don't want to think I've lost a son,
so much as...
...gained a daughter.
For, since the tragic death of her father...
He's not quite dead!
Since the near fatal wounding
of her father...
He's getting better!
For, since her own father...
...who, when he seemed about to recover...
...suddenly felt the icy hand of death
upon him.
He's died!
I want his only daughter to look upon me...
...as her own dad, in a very real,
and legally binding sense.
And I feel sure that the merger...
The union between the Princess...
...and the brave but dangerous
Sir Lancelot of Camelot...
. What?
. Look, the dead Prince!
. He's not quite dead!
. I feel much better.
You fell out of the tall tower, you creep!
. No, I was saved at the last minute.
. How?
I'll tell you.
Not like that! Not like that.
"He's going tell
He's going to tell"
Quickly, sir, come this way!
No, it's not right for my idiom.
I must escape more...
. Dramatically, sir?
. Dramatically.
Excuse me,
could somebody give me a push, please?
Old crone!
Is there anywhere in this town
where we could buy a shrubbery?
. Who sent you?
. The knights who say, "Ni"!
No! We have no shrubberies here.
If you do not tell us where we can buy
a shrubbery, my friend and I...
...will say...
We will say, "Ni."
Do your worst!
Very well.
If you will not assist us voluntarily...
...Ni!
. No!
Never. No shrubberies.
. Ni!
. Noo!
No, it's not that, it's "Ni."
No, you're not doing it properly.
. Ni.
. You've got it.
. Ni!
Are you saying "Ni" to that old woman?
Yes.
What sad times are these when passing
ruffians can say, "Ni" at will to old ladies.
There is a pestilence upon this land.
Nothing is sacred.
Even those who arrange shrubberies
are under considerable economic stress...
...at this period in history.
. Did you say "shrubberies"?
. Yes.
Shrubberies are my trade.
I am a shrubber.
My name is Roger the Shrubber.
I arrange, design, and sell shrubberies.
. Ni!
. No!
Knights of Ni,
we have brought you your shrubbery.
. May we go?
. It is a good shrubbery.
I like the laurels particularly.
But there is one small problem.
What is that?
We are now no longer
the knights who say "Ni."
We are now the knights who say:
"Ekke Ekke Ekke Ptang Zoo Boing"!
Therefore, we must give you a test.
What's is this test,
knights who until recently said "Ni"?
Firstly, you must find...
...another shrubbery!
Not another shrubbery!
Then you must bring it here
beside this shrubbery.
Higher, so you get the two. Level effect,
a path going down the middle.
A path! A path!
Then, when you have found
the shrubberies...
...you must cut down
the mightiest tree in the forest...
...with a herring!
. We shall do no such thing.
. Please.
Cut down a tree with a herring?
It can't be done.
. Don't say that word.
. What word?
I cannot tell. Suffice to say...
...it's one of the words
the knights of Ni cannot hear.
How can we not say the word
if you don't tell us what it is?
. He did it again.
. What? "Is"?
You wouldn't get very far in life
not saying "is."
My liege, it's Robin.
"He's jacking it in and packing it up
And sneaking away and buggering up
"And chickening out and pissing a pot
Yes, bravely he is throwing in the sponge"
. Robin.
. My liege.
It's good to see you.
You haven't given up your quest
for the Holy Grail?
."He is sneaking away and..."
. Shut up!
. No, far from it.
. You said the word again.
I was looking for it here in this forest.
. No, it is far from this place.
. Stop saying the word!
. The word we cannot hear!
. Stop it!
. He said, "it" again!
. That's it!
I've said, "it." I've said, "it."
I've said, "it" again!
That's three "its"!
And so Arthur and Bedevere and
Sir Robin set out on their search to find...
... the enchanter of whom
the old man had spoken in Scene 24.
Beyond the forest
they met Lancelot and Galahad...
... and there was much rejoicing.
In the frozen land of Nador...
... they were forced to eat
Robin's minstrels.
And there was much rejoicing.
A year passed.
Winter changed into spring.
Spring changed into summer.
Summer changed back into winter...
... and winter gave spring and summer
a miss and went straight on into autumn.
Until one day.
Knights...
...forward!
What manner of man are you,
that can summon up fire...
...without flint or tinder?
. I am an enchanter.
. By what name are you known?
. There are some who call me...
...Tim.
. Greetings, Tim the enchanter!
Greetings, King Arthur.
. You know my name?
. I do.
You seek the Holy Grail.
That is our quest.
You know much that is hidden, Tim.
Quite.
Yes, we are looking for the Holy Grail.
. Our quest is to find the Holy Grail.
. Yes, it is.
. And so we're looking for it.
. Yes, we are.
. We have been for some time.
. Ages.
So, anything you could do to help
would be...
: : : very: : :
...helpful.
. Look, can you tell us where...
Fine, I don't want to waste
any more of your time...
...but I don't suppose you could tell us
where we might find a...
A what?
A grail?
Yes, I think so.
Yes.
Yes!
. Thank you.
. Splendid!
Look, you're a busy man...
Yes, I can help you find the Holy Grail.
To the north, there lies a cave.
The Cave of Caerbannog.
Wherein, carved in mystic runes,
upon the very living rock...
...the last words
of Olfin Bedwere of Rheged...
...make plain the last resting place
of the most Holy Grail.
. Where could we find this cave, Tim?
. Follow!
But follow only if ye be men of valour.
For the entrance to this cave
is guarded by a creature...
...so foul, so cruel...
...that no man yet
has fought with it and lived.
Bones of full 50 men lie strewn
about its lair. So, brave knights...
...if you do doubt your courage
or your strength, come no further...
...for death awaits you all
with nasty, big, pointy teeth.
What an eccentric performance!
They're nervous, sire.
Then we'd best leave them here
and carry on, on foot.
Dismount!
Behold the Cave of Caerbannog!
. Right, keep me covered.
. What with?
. Just keep me covered.
. Too late.
There he is!
. Where?
. There.
. What, behind the rabbit?
. It is the rabbit.
. You silly sod!
. What?
You got us all worked up.
That's no ordinary rabbit.
That's the most foul, cruel and
bad. Tempered rodent you ever set eyes on.
You tit! I soiled my armour
I was so scared!
Look, that rabbit's got
a vicious streak a mile wide.
. It's a killer!
. Get stuffed.
. He'll do you up a treat, mate!
. Yeah?
. You manky Scots git!
. I'm warning you.
. What's he do? Nibble your bum?
. He's got huge, sharp...
It can leap about...
. Look at the bones!
. Go on, Bors, chop its head off.
Right. Silly little bleeder.
One rabbit stew coming right up.
Look!
. Jesus Christ!
. I warned you!
. I've done it again.
. I warned you.
But did you listen to me?
No, you knew it all, didn't you?
It's just a harmless little bunny, isn't it?
Well, it's always the same.
. I always...
. Shut up!
Charge!
Run away!
. How many did we lose?
. Gawain.
. Ector.
. And Bors. That's five.
. Three.
We better not risk another frontal assault,
that rabbit's dynamite.
Would it help to confuse it
if we run away more?
. Shut up and change your armour.
. Let us taunt it.
It may become so cross,
that it will make a mistake.
Like what?
Well...
. Have we got bows?
. No.
. We have the Holy Hand Grenade.
. Yes, of course!
The Holy Hand Grenade of Antioch.
It's one of the sacred relics
Brother Maynard carries.
Brother Maynard!
Bring up the Holy Hand Grenade.
How does it...
How does it work?
. I know not, my liege.
. Consult the Book of Armaments.
Armaments 2: 9.21.
"And St. Attila raised the hand grenade
up on high, saying:
"'O Lord, bless this thy hand grenade,
that with it thou mayest...
"'... blow thine enemies
to tiny bits, in thy mercy.'
"And the Lord did grin
and the people did feast upon...
"...the lambs and sloths and carp
and anchovies and orangutans...
"...and breakfast cereals
and fruit bats and..."
Skip a bit, Brother.
"The Lord spake, saying,
'First shalt thou take out the Holy Pin...
"'... then shalt thou count to three,
no more, no less.
"'Three shalt be the number
thou shalt count...
"'... and the number
of the counting shalt be three.
"'Four shalt thou not count,
neither count thou two...
"'... excepting that thou then
proceed to three.
"'Five is right out.
"'Once the number three,
being the third number be reached...
"'... then lobbest thou
thy Holy Hand Grenade of Antioch...
"'... towards thy foe,
who, being naughty in my sight...
"'... shall snuff it."'
Amen.
Right.
One, two, five!
. Three, sir!
. Three!
There! Look!
What does it say? What language is that?
Brother Maynard, you're our scholar.
It is Aramaic!
Of course. Joseph of Arimathea!
. Of course.
. What does it say?
It reads, "Here may be found...
"...the last words of Joseph of Arimathea:
"'He who is valiant and pure of spirit...
"'... may find the Holy Grail...
"'... in the Castle of Aaargh."'
What?
"The Castle of Aaargh."
What is that?
He must have died while carving it.
. Come on!
. That's what it says.
Look, if he was dying,
he wouldn't bother to carve "Aaargh."
. He'd just say it.
. That's what's carved in the rock.
. Perhaps he was dictating it.
. Shut up!
. Does it say anything else?
. No!
Just "Aaargh."
Aaargh.
Do you suppose he meant the Camargue?
. Where's that?
. In France, I think.
. Isn't there a St. Aaargh's in Cornwall?
. No, that's St. Ives.
St. Ives.
No, "Aaargh." At the back of the throat.
No, in surprise and alarm!
. You mean a sort of a "Ah!"
. Yes, that's right.
My God!
It's the Legendary Black Beast of Aaargh!
That's it! Run away!
We've lost him.
As the horrendous Black Beast
lunged forward...
...escape for Arthur
and his knights seemed hopeless.
When, suddenly, the animator
suffered a fatal heart attack.
The cartoon peril was no more.
The quest for the Holy Grail
could continue.
There it is!
. The Bridge of Death.
. Great.
Look! There's the old man from Scene 24.
. What's he doing here?
. He is the keeper of the Bridge of Death.
He asks each traveller five questions.
. Three questions.
. He who answers the five questions...
. Three questions, may cross in safety.
. What if you get a question wrong?
Then you are cast
into the gorge of eternal peril.
. Oh, wacko.
. Who's going to answer the questions?
Brave Sir Robin, you go.
I've got a great idea:
Why doesn't Lancelot go?
Yes, let me go, my liege.
I will take him single. Handed.
. I shall make a feint to the northeast...
. Hang on!
. Just answer the five questions...
. Three questions.
Three questions, as best you can.
And we shall watch and pray.
I understand, my liege.
Good luck, brave Sir Lancelot.
God be with you.
Stop!
Who would cross the Bridge of Death,
must answer me these questions three.
Ere the other side he see.
Ask me the questions, bridgekeeper.
I'm not afraid.
. What is your name?
. My name is Sir Lancelot of Camelot.
What is your quest?
To seek the Holy Grail.
What is your favourite colour?
. Blue.
. Right. Off you go.
Well, thank you very much.
That's easy.
Stop.
Who approacheth the Bridge of Death,
must answer me these questions three.
Ere the other side he see.
Ask me the questions, bridgekeeper.
I'm not afraid.
. What is your name?
. Sir Robin of Camelot.
. What is your quest?
. To seek the Holy Grail.
What is the capital of Assyria?
I don't know that!
Stop!
. What is your name?
. Sir Galahad of Camelot.
. What is your quest?
. I seek the Grail.
. What is your favourite colour?
. Blue.
No! Yellow!
Stop!
. What is your name?
. It is Arthur, King of the Britons.
. What is your quest?
. To seek the Holy Grail.
What is the air. Speed velocity
of an unladen swallow?
What do you mean?
An African or European swallow?
I don't know that!
How do you know
so much about swallows?
You have to know these things
when you're a king.
Lancelot!
The Castle Aaargh. Our quest is at an end.
God be praised.
Almighty God...
...we thank thee, that thou hast vouchsafed
to us the most holy...
Jesus Christ!
Dirty English knights.
Monsieur Arthur King,
who has the brain of a duck.
So, we French fellows
outwit you a second time.
How dare you profane this place
with your presence?
I command you,
in the name of the knights of Camelot...
...to open the doors of this sacred castle...
...to which God himself has guided us.
How you English say?
I'll unclog my nose in your direction.
Sons of a window. Dresser!
So, you think you could
out. Clever us French folk...
...with your silly knees. Bent,
running about, advancing behaviour.
I wave my private parts at your aunties.
You cheesy lot of second. Hand,
electric donkey. Bottom biters!
In the name of the Lord...
...we demand entrance
to this sacred castle!
No chance, English bed. Wetting types.
I burst my pimples at you, and call your
door. Opening request a silly thing!
You tiny. Brained wipers
of other people's bottoms.
If you'll not open this door,
we shall take this castle by force!
In the name of God and the glory of our...
Right! That settles it!
Depart at this time,
and don't be approaching any more...
...or we fire arrows into your heads,
and make castanets out of your testicles.
Walk away, just ignore them.
And now remain gone,
illegitimate. Faced bugger. Folk!
And, if you think you got a nasty
taunting this time, you ain't heard...
...nothing yet, dirty English knights!
. We shall attack at once.
. Yes, my liege.
Stand by for attack!
French persons!
Today the blood of many a valiant knight
shall be avenged.
In the name of God,
we shall not stop our fight...
...till each one of you lies dead,
and the Holy Grail...
...returns to those whom God has chosen.
Charge!
Yes, they're the ones, I'm sure.
. Come on.
. Put this man in the van.
. Put him in the van.
. Get a blanket over that one.
Come on, back! Right back!
That's an offensive weapon, that is.
All right, sonny, that's enough.
Pack that in.